# ARAVINDHAN VENKATESWARAN

West saidapet, Chennai - 600015 | +91-9841612186 | <u>alexaravindh3453@gmail.com</u>

#### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Multi-tasking IT Infra Engineer with a background in remote desktop support and IT Services. A determined employee with over 2.5 years of experience in successfully handling level 2 & 3 Incidents and finding ways to provide first call resolution. Committed to remaining poised and calm in high pressure situations.

#### Education

- · Major: BCA at Tagore college of Arts and Science, Madras University
- · Minor: Diploma of E- commerce Digital Marketing, Madras University
- · Related coursework: C, C++ Language

#### **SCHOOL**

- · Major:12th from Chennai Boys Higher Secondary School
- · Minor: 10th from Chennai Boys Higher Secondary School

#### COMMUNICATION

٠	ENGLISH	YES	YES	YES
	TAMIL	YES	YES	YES
	TELUGU	YES	YES	YES

# **WORK HISTORY**

# IT EXECUTIVE | FUSSION PVT LTD | DATE JULY2019 - SEP2020

- Experience as an Desktop support Engineer (Field Engineer)
- Configured hardware, devices and software to set up work stations for employees
- Were we support small level of industries
- Patched software and installed new versions to eliminate security problems and protect data.
- Have good work experience on Service-Now ticketing tool
- Have good knowledge on installing software and running updates on client's system.
- Analyzed both Hardware and software issues using ping checks

### IT EXECUTIVE | EUREKA OUTSOURCING SOLUTIONS | DATE OCT2020 - AUG2021

- Provided technical troubleshooting and problem solving for clients with installed equipment/system issues.
- Followed up with clients to ensure optimal customer satisfaction following support engagement and problem resolution.

- Documented all transactions and support interactions in system for future reference and addition to knowledge base.
- Demonstrated professionalism and courtesy with customers while working to resolve complaints, problems or respond to questions.
- Responded to support requests from end users and patiently walked individuals through basic troubleshooting tasks.
- Provided solutions to operations issues for users, working closely via phone, email with end users.

## SENIOR ENGINEER(EUS) | MICROLAND | DATE AUG2020 - TILL DATE

- Managing Incident Queue and making team resolve the incidents before SLA breach.
- Weekly Client call handling and producing Incident and Task Reports
- BMC Remedy, Service now hands-on experience.
- Deep dive analysis on tickets and follow-ups on ageing tickets.
- Have worked on reducing incidents by educating the users on how to use self-service, Virtual assistant tools.
- Have conducted Digital Dexterity sessions to global users to reduce service desk tickets and incidents
- Installation of Software's through SM tools and manual installations.
- Handling escalated incidents and tasks
- Resolving p1 and p2 tickets by joining bridge call with multiple teams.
- Troubleshooting on Microsoft office 365,outlook
- Maintaining accurate hardware and software inventory and configuration information
- Shift roster for team in round robin method Weekly Client call handling and producing Incident and Task Reports
- Bridge Call Organizing
- Citrix
- Office 365
- Outlook Troubleshooting
- Performance analysis
- Recording
- Reporting
- SLA
- Software installation

# Networking

- Cisco Router configuration. L2 & L3 Switches, V-Lan configure & maintenance.
- RJ 11& RJ 45 Network cable crimping.
- Install and support LANs, WANs, network segments, Internet, and intranet systems.
- Install and maintain network hardware and software.
- Monitor networks to ensure security and availability to specific users.
- Evaluate and modify system's performance.
- Determine network and system requirements.

• Maintain integrity of the network, server deployment, and security.

# ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

The Objective is to restore normal service operation as quickly as possible to minimize the impact to business operations. Responsibilities: Responsible for planning and coordinating all the activities required to perform, monitor and report on the process.

# **HOBBIES**

- Playing chess and also participate on district level chess tournament.
- Exploring new restaurant's with friends.

### PERSONAL PROFILE

Date of Birth : 20.05.1997

Address : NO 19/9 New Colony 3rd Cross Street, West Saidapet, Chennai – 600015.

DECALARATION:

I hereby declare that the information furnished above is true to the best of my knowledge.

DATE:	
PLACE:	ARAVINDHAN V